本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流之用 更多中日双语字幕，请登录 www.kamigami.org  台本：卷 　翻译:mam  校对: maize　时间轴：花开  后期：娜夏
This is a work of fiction. Names, characters,
places and incidents either are products of the
author’s imagination or are used fictitiously. Any
resemblance to actual events or locales or
persons, living or dead, is entirely coincidental.
トレボー１より ワイバーンへ
こちら ワイバーン どうした
Turbo-1 to Wyvern.
北西部に 巨大移動物体を確認
Wyvern here. What is it?
巨大移動物体？
Investigating a large moving object to the northwest.
『居ル夫 』による情報検索 操作不可
A large moving object?
推定１５ｍ以上あると思われます
Using Iru-O for information retrieval operations is impossible.
どうしますか
Estimated height is above 15m.
気にするな
How will you proceed?
トレボーは 予定どおり その場で待機 発射準備に専念しろ
Disregard it. We're concentrating on the launch.
I'm on standby at the spot just like we planned.
発射まで４７分
液体燃料 準備完了
47 minutes until launch.
風速１．０ 降雨なし
Liquid fuel ready.
巨大移動物体 このままだと 間もなく 射場に到着
Wind speed at 1.0 knots. No rain.
ミサイルの使用を要請します
The large moving object will soon arrive at the launch site.
ワイバーンより トレボーへ
Requesting permission to launch missiles.
判断は こちらで下す 持ち場を離れるな
Wyvern to Turbo.
I'll make the final decision here.
Do not leave your positions.
来たか
ミサ姉…
It's here.
カイ…お姉ちゃん…
Misa!
部長
分かってる
Kai... Sis...
President.
I know.
残酷なる時は いつか
In the end, time unforgiving
契約の地さえ引き裂くの
Will draw the blood of covenant
たくさんが生み出す恐怖
Everything scatters, leaving void
真理のために今ここにいるよ
意外なCrazy
But we're here for the greater good
We Meet
目眩くこのシーン うかつな選択
Crazier than everyone, we need to dazzle
The stage with our careless justice
浮かび行く景色はやがて鮮やかに
And the scenery floating by becomes clearer
時間をすり抜ける
咆筺のメシア
As the Messiah of the Shoutbox slips through time
笑って 泣いて
僕らの一つの夢
Laugh and cry for our one and only dream
願って 叫んで
どこまでも遠くへ
Laugh and cry for our one and only dream
Pray, shout, and struggle right down to the end
走って 飛ばして
気持ちの集まる場所
Pray, shout, and struggle right down to the end
Run and break that place where feelings gather
愛しすぎるこの空の下で
Under this sky, oh so dear
明日を証明したくて
We're fighting for the future
This is our game now
AR decoy: Activate!
ＡＲデコイ 起動
こ…これが戦場かっ
I-Is this a battlefield?
As expected of Sawada.
でも さすが 澤田キュン
Everyone okay?
みんな 大丈夫？
Yeah, we're good.
はい
大丈夫
どうやら ＡＲデコイ 効果ありですね
The AR decoys are really effective.
Now what?
どうする？
With the missiles out of the picture, there's nothing to be scared of.
ミサイルが 効かないなら 怖いものは ないな
近づくか？
Should we close in?
No. We haven't disabled its missiles.
いえ ミサイルが 全て 無効になったわけではありません
The decoys interfere with Iru-O and
disguise themselves as the real thing.
ＡＲデコイは 居ル夫 に 干渉して ＡＲを本物と思わせ
They make targeting harder.
的を絞りにくくするもの
Like a cloning technique, so to speak.
いわば 分身の術みたいなものです
Thanks to them, the probability of hitting the real one is reduced.
当たる確率は低いですが 偶然本物を捉えることも 当然ある
However, they could land a hit if they're lucky.
き…き…来たー
I-I-It's here!
アキちゃん ボタン
Aki, the button!
Quickly!
早く
カイ
Kai!
大丈夫…
I'm okay.
The pile bunker!
パイルバンカーが…まだ 右がある
The right side is still there!
Are you running, Misa?
逃げるのか ミサ姉
ＳＵＭＥＲＡＧＩ 巨大移動物体と交戦中
The SUMERAGI is battling with the large moving object.
Continue with the rocket launch as planned.
ロケットに異常なし カウント続行
I'll attack them when I see a chance.
隙を見て 私が突っ込みます 援護してください
Please back me up.
あと…３０分…
Thirty minutes left...
You can't shoot missiles from this range.
この距離なら ミサイルは撃てない
Right, Misa?
そうだろ？ ミサ姉
なっ 何だよ これ？
What the hell?
You can do it!
頑張ってください
Don't worry about it.
心配すんな
負けねえよ 俺が調整したんだ
He won't lose. I set that machine up.
Let the monopole motors howl!
うなりやがれ モノポールモーター
Go!
いっけぇぇぇぇ
We did it!
やった
まだです
Not yet!
Aki!
アキちゃん
Take this!
この…
Gunvarrel Ankh Striker!
ガンヴァルアンクストライカー
Direct hit!
当たった
That must've destroyed its cameras.
カメラ部分を 破壊したはずです これなら…
We can win.
Misa, you can hear me, can't you?
ミサ姉 聞こえてるんでしょ？
出てきなよ
Get out! Get out and tell Aki yourself!
出てきて アキちゃんに…
アキちゃんに 自分の口から 話しなよ
Tell her what happened! Why you abandoned the GunPro-1!
何があったのか 何で ガンつくを捨てたのか
Why you said all that!
何で あんなこと言ったのか…
Tell her all that!
全部 全部 話しなよ
She chased after you to hear that!
それを聞くために アキちゃんは 追い掛けてきたんだ
She caught up to you!
追い付いたんだ
Kai...
カイ…
Stop running away, Misa!
逃げるなよ ミサ姉
Sadly, you were a bit late.
残念ながら 一歩 遅かったよ
Her consciousness has already faded.
彼女の意識は すでに 崩壊してしまった
I sunk her into the darkness already.
僕が 闇に沈めたからね
Sis...
お姉ちゃん…
じ…自爆？
Is it blowing itself up?
Look!
見ろ
She's now just a mindless doll.
彼女は 意識を持たぬ 操り人形さ
Mine... Kimijima Kou's.
この 君島コウのね
Kimijima Kou.
君島コウ…
This is team B. We retook the control room.
こちら Ｂ班
コントロールルームの 奪還に成功
We will proceed with aborting the rocket launch sequence now.
これから ロケット発射 中止作業に移ります
It's pointless. The rocket won't stop.
無駄だよ ロケットは止まらない
何…？
What?
The experiment must end successfully.
実験は 成功させなければ ならないからね
It's fast!
速い
跳んだ
It jumped?
みんな 逃げて
Run!
I died. I just died. I totally just died.
私 死んだ はい 死んだ 今 死んだ
Is everyone okay?
みんな 大丈夫？
I'm alive.
何とか でも…
But...
Now we can only rely on the built-in batteries.
残念ですが 後は 内蔵バッテリーに 頼るしかありません
駆動時間は およそ５分
It can only operate for about five minutes.
Akiho, it doesn't work.
あき穂ちゃん
駄目です
The computer won't accept my launch cancel command, no matter how many times I try.
何度やっても打ち上げ中止コマンドを 受け付けません
The admin is blocking it.
管理者によって ブロックされています
現在の管理者 君島コウ
And the current admin is... Kimijima Kou.
I sacrificed lots of time and even my life for this experiment.
これだけ長い時間と僕の命まで懸けた実験なんだ
I will make it succeed, no matter what.
必ず成功させる
必ずね
No matter what.
W-What?!
な…な…何ぞ
どうしたんだ？
What's wrong?
I-I-I-I-It's here!
き…き…き…きたーっ
Sawada! It's happening!
澤田キュン ｋｔｋｒ
Koujiro, we don't have time for—
神代さん ふざけてる場合じゃ…
No! He sent me a program!
ち…違う プログラム きた
This can erase Kimijima Kou!
君島コウを除去する
What?!
何だって ？
After installing, lock Kimijima's AR on the PokeCom's screen.
作用させるには インストール後
君島のＡＲを ポケコンの画面に 映している状態で ロックする
でも それ以前に
But before installing,  you need to reboot your PokeCom.
インストールには ポケコンの再起動が ひ…必要
Reboot?
再起動？
Yeah. Then we'll have to lure my sister out of the cockpit somehow.
うん そしたら 何とかしてコックピットから お姉ちゃんを引きずり出すの
Kimijima Kou will definitely appear there.
必ず 君島コウが映るはずだから
Please let him not notice...
気付くなよ…
Ten minutes left.
残り１０分…
All my communications have been cut off.
通信が 完全に途絶えた 何か小細工を したようだね
It would seem they played a trick without me noticing.
No reaction?
反応しない？
き…来たよ
He's coming!
Did he notice?
気付かれたか？
Kai!
カイ
President, Yashio's still rebooting!
部長 八汐先輩は 再起動中です
He can't see the enemy's movement!
向こうの動きが まったく見えてません
カイ…
Kai...
部長
President!
Sis... Sis...
お姉ちゃん…お姉ちゃん…
Sis!
お姉ちゃーん
Stop! Sis! It's me! Aki!
止まって
止まって お姉ちゃん
うちだよ アキだよ
お姉ちゃーん
Sis!
バカな…まだ 意識があるというのか？
Impossible.
She's still got fragments of her consciousness?
アキちゃん 下がって
Fall back, Aki!
Come on, Misa!
来いよ ミサ姉
Come on, attack!
ほら 攻めてきなよ
You're not the type to go on TV and share your love with the world!
ミサ姉は テレビに出て 愛想 振りまいてるような タイプじゃないだろ？
澄ました顔して 容赦なく パーフェクト勝ちしてくるようなえぐい女でしょ
You're a heartless woman who aims for a perfect victory while smirking confidently!
Kai...
カイ…
You're the crazy kinda chick who loves robot anime despite being a girl,
女子のくせに ロボットアニメ好きで
and you seriously wanted to build a giant robot here at the end of the world.
こんな田舎で マジで 巨大ロボを造ろうとして
All while dragging everyone else along too!
周りを巻き込んじゃうような バカ女でしょうが
Do you even have the right stuff anymore?!
今のあんたに ライトスタッフがあるのかよ？
Answer, Misa!
答えろ ミサ姉
それ以上 好き放題 言うと…
Say a single word more,
and I'll crush you!
つぶすわよ
さあ ここからは 俺たちのゲームだ
This is our game now.
分かってるよ ミサ姉
I get it, Misa. It's always been like that in Kill-Ballad.
『キルバラ』のとき いつも そうだった
アキちゃん
Aki!
Misa always
ミサ姉は 必ず…
ducks 4 units to the right!
４フレ 右に よけるんだよ
お姉ちゃん
Sis!
まったく
Honestly...
残念だが みさ希は もう いない
Too bad. Misaki's already gone.
This time...
今度こそ…
Look!
見てよ
It's the GunPro-1!
ガンつく１だよ
It's the robot you built!
お姉ちゃんが造っていた ロボットだよ
Is that what you came here to tell me?
そんなことを 言いに来たのかい？
It's the robot you and I and all of us put all our heart into!
お姉ちゃんと うちとみんなの思いが こもった ロボットだよ
動いてるんだよ
It's moving!
It's trying to save the world!
世界を救おうとしているんだよ
It'd seem you and your sister both have the most peculiar minds—
どうやら 姉妹 揃って 不思議な精神の持ち主…
これは…？
What?
Do you remember?
覚えてる？
When dad first showed me robots, you said,
うちが 初めて お父さんに ロボットを見せてもらったとき
お姉ちゃん こう言ったんだよ
"I love robots."
私 ロボットが好き
"I love them the most."
世界で一番 好きだもん
今でも…好き？
Do you still love them?
Do you still love robots more than anything in the world?
お姉ちゃん 今でも 世界で一番 ロボットが好き？
Shut up!
黙れー
Get lost!
消えろー
あと…
I was... so close...
あと少しだったのに
Too bad...
残念だよ
But there will be a second and third me, and eventually...
だが…第２ 第３の僕が…いずれ…
Right.
そうだね…
But... justice is still gonna win for sure.
でも…
それでも 正義は 必ず勝つらしいよ
Our club president said so.
俺たちの部長が そう言ってた
That might be true.
そうかも…しれないね…
お姉ちゃん
Sis!
Aki...
アキ…
Sis...
お姉ちゃん…
ありがとう
Thank you!
管理者 君島コウから変わりました
Kimijima Kou is no longer the administrator!
中止コマンド 入力
Inputting cancel command!
Please!
お願い
Countdown stopped! Launch prevented!
カウント ストップ…ロケット発射阻止 成功です
They did it!
き…きたー
や…やった… 痛っ
H-Hell yeah!
Ouch!
インパクトォォォ
Quite an impact!
ボインダー
Impact!
いいロックじゃねえか
Well rocked.
やった
こら 静かにしなさい まったく…
Calm yourselves! For God's sake.
Aki!
アキちゃん ミサ姉は？
How's she?
She's fine.
大丈夫 気を失ってるだけ
She just passed out.
カイ
Kai, let's go back to the hangar!
ハンガーに帰ろう
All those unexpected moments
それはふとした瞬間に
As you mumble on and on
君がつぶやくいくつもの言葉
Will overcome even my standards
それがいつしか価値観さえも
In the end
超えてしまうんだよ
All those goodbyes we said
いくつもの別れを告げ 僕らは
As we climb the stairway to the future
明日への階段をのぼる
Just as raindrops fall no matter what we do
とめどなく零れ落ちる雫も
Light will always hold this planet together
光が照らすなら この星は繋がっている
Lives gather as if by some miracle
奇跡のように命が集まって
Showing the outline of a lively scene
にぎやかな景色は輪郭になる
An epilogue so bright it brings tears to our eyes
泣きたい眩しいエピローグ
The sky painted by the hearts of those looking up
取り上げる思いが
描いた空
The wind blows gently stroking
柔らかな風が吹き
Turning into a new path
新しい道となり
A path that will always
いつだってその道は
Lead us to this place
この場所に繋がってる
Say, Kai...
ねえ カイ…
Hm?
What're you gonna do now?
カイは これから どうするの？
What do you mean?
これからって？
Kill-Ballad
Well, after we graduate from school and become adults.
学校 卒業して 大人になったら
Are you sure you want to uninstall this application?
Erasing
何で そんなこと聞くの？
Why are you asking me that?
Erased
何となく
Just curious.
Let's see...
そうだな…
Let's aim high again.
もう一度 目指してみますか
何？ 何？
Huh? What?
Right, Misa?
なあ ミサ姉
Our dream,
俺たちの夢は
俺たちのロボは
our robot...
みんなの希望になってたよ
could become everyone's hope.
Welcome back,               TaneHigh Robotics Club!!
It could protect everyone's smiles.
みんなの笑顔を 守れたよ
5! 4! 3! 2! 1!
５…４…３…２…
１…０
Zero!
Thanks for watching!!